{
    "1": {
        "question" : "Who was the captain of Voyager?",
        "answer" : "b",
        "a" : "Spock",
        "b" : "Katherine Janeway",
        "c" : "James Kirk",
        "d" : "Angelina Jolie",
        "e" : "None of the above"
    },
    "2": {
        "question" : "What happened to Voyager such that they couldn't go home?",
        "answer" : "c",
        "a" : "Trapped behind energy field",
        "b" : "Destroyed by the Borg",
        "c" : "Went thru a worm hole to the Delta quadrant",
        "d" : "Stuck in a black hole",
        "e" : "None of the above"
    },
    "3": {
        "question" : "The Omega Directive was created by Starfleet. What were all Starfleet Captains trained to do if an Omega Molecule is detected?",
        "answer" : "c",
        "a" : "The Omega molecule, created on Jupiter station, escaped during testing and holds starfleets highest held secrets and could be extremely dangerous if it falls into enemy hands.",
        "b" : "Scan and record ONLY. Do NOT disturb an Omega molecule because of it's highly unstable nature.",
        "c" : "Destroy the Omega molecule in a controlled manner because it can cause an entire quadrant to become non space faring.",
        "d" : "The Omega molecule is a highly sought after molecule because it is so rare and if they find one, capture it at all costs.",
        "e" : "None of the above"
    },
    "4": {
        "question" : "What class starship is Voyager?",
        "answer" : "a",
        "a" : "Intrepid Class",
        "b" : "Constitution Class",
        "c" : "Defiant Class",
        "d" : "Constellation Class",
        "e" : "Excelsior Class"
    },
    "5": {
        "question" : "How far did Voyager get flung by the Caretaker?",
        "answer" : "d",
        "a" : "185,000 Light Years",
        "b" : "10,000 Light Years",
        "c" : "150,000 Light Years",
        "d" : "50,000 Light Years",
        "e" : "70,000 Light Years"
    },
    "6": {
        "question" : "Which species was NOT found in the Delta quadrant?",
        "answer" : "d",
        "a" : "Ocampa",
        "b" : "Vidiians",
        "c" : "Talaxian",
        "d" : "Bajoran",
        "e" : "Kazon"
    },
    "7": {
        "question" : "What is the average life span of an Ocampa?",
        "answer" : "e",
        "a" : "Between 25-30 years",
        "b" : "18 years",
        "c" : "50 years",
        "d" : "90 years",
        "e" : "9 years"
    },
    "8": {
        "question" : "When the caretakers mate was discovered, the mate:",
        "answer" : "d",
        "a" : "Turned out to be a myth, created by the Ocampa",
        "b" : "Sent them home in the seventh season and that's how the show ended",
        "c" : "Was in the form of a little boy and helped knock some time off their journey",
        "d" : "Was in the form of a little girl and thought the Voyager crew had killed the caretaker",
        "e" : "None of the above"
    },
    "9": {
        "question" : "Which officer acted disruptive, showing up tardy and having a bad attitude so he could act as though he wanted to leave Voyager to draw out the Kazon spy?",
        "answer" : "c",
        "a" : "Harry Kim",
        "b" : "B'Elana Torres",
        "c" : "Tom Paris",
        "d" : "Tuvok",
        "e" : "Neelix"
    },
    "10": {
        "question" : "When the doctor program was left running for so long, his matrix started to degrade into a cascading failure. How did he survive?",
        "answer" : "b",
        "a" : "They simply rebooted his program.",
        "b" : "Kes used the diagnostic program as a foundation for a new matrix and grafted onto it the doctors old matrix",
        "c" : "The doctor, working alone, went into a kind of fantasy world to sort out his feelings which fixed the problem",
        "d" : "They first had to remove all of his extra programming such as singing and photography and then rebooted him",
        "e" : "None of the above"
    },
    "11": {
        "question" : "Q, the son of Q, befriended which Voyager inhabitant?",
        "answer" : "a",
        "a" : "Icheb",
        "b" : "Tom Paris",
        "c" : "Seven of Nine",
        "d" : "Naomi Wildman",
        "e" : "Chakotay"
    },
    "12": {
        "question" : "Commander Chakotay and Captain Janeway were both left on a planet to potentially live the rest of their lives when they couldn't find a cure for their disease. What animal type was Janeway close to befriending?",
        "answer" : "c",
        "a" : "An Amphibian",
        "b" : "A Crustacean",
        "c" : "A Primate",
        "d" : "A Reptile",
        "e" : "A Marsupial"
    }
}
